[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Dame Sylvia breathing heavily]
[distorted voice speaking]
[♪ music stops]
[Boy Kavalier] "All children,
except one, grow up.
They soon know that they will grow up,
and the way Wendy knew was this.
One day, when she was two years old,
she was playing in a garden."
[Wendy rattling]
[Boy Kavalier] "And she plucked another
flower and ran with it to her mother."
[Wendy screeches]
"I suppose
she must have looked rather delightful,
for Mrs. Darling
put her hand to her heart and cried,
'Oh, why can't you remain
like this forever?'
This was all that passed
between them on the subject,
but henceforth,
Wendy knew that she must grow up.
You always know after you're two.
Two is the beginning of the end."
[Wendy rattling]
[screeching]
[rattling, screeching]
-[Wendy rattling]
-[creature screeches]
[screeching]
You sure she's safe?
[Kirsh] She killed an adult male
single-handed.
This one's a child behind three inches
of steel and tempered glass.
Safe isn't always about bodies.
So you're worried about what,
her intellect, her emotions?
Smee told me that
he can go two years without recharging.
What other maintenance
do they need, the hybrids?
Why?
[stutters] I'm saying…
one day, she's gonna graduate,
right, from this place,
and when she does, she's gonna need
someone to take care of her.
That's like an onion asking,
"How do I take care of a star?"
Fine. Sure.
You think
he's gonna let you take her with you?
No. Uh…
Maybe.
To do what?
Live.
Be a family.
Your sister has potential
to invent faster than light travel
and explore the stars
for thousands of years,
and you want her to be a family?
She's just a kid.
Keep telling yourself that.
-[Kirsh punching keys]
-[door opens]
[creature screeching]
[machine humming]
[machine beeping]
[beeping stops]
[Arthur] Like I said, it's not mechanical.
Is she…
I have her in charging mode.
She can't hear us.
-So what did she say exactly?
-[Dame Sylvia sighs]
She said she was pregnant.
Pregnant.
-[Dame Sylvia] She's had a traumatic--
-Is that what I'm supposed to tell him?
She's always been emotional.
[chuckles] You remember.
I thought we adjusted for that.
We did, in the architecture…
just not enough, clearly.
So how do we fix her?
In time, with enough therapy.
No.
[Dame Sylvia] Look, she's…
As I said, there's trauma in her past.
We knew that when we chose her.
I can help her. I just need time.
No. You're going in.
Reset her to before the tower.
Full memory wipe.
Then I want you to dial back her reactions
to stimulus, slow her processing speed.
You're talking about
fundamentally altering her personality.
That's against every principle
of the program.
[Atom Eins] Don't be dramatic.
You said it yourself.
She's a child in distress.
We're helping her.
You should be grateful we have the tools.
We don't know what impact
this would have on her identity,
on her functioning psychology.
We could be making it worse.
[Atom Eins] Listen to me, both of you.
This unit is going
to be smiling and waving from the stage
three weeks from now.
And when the information architects
of The Five
talk to her over canapes and cocktails,
I want her to be calm and charming,
just like the others.
We've come too far to fail now
just because you don't have the stomach
to bring this home.
I won-I won't do it.
Excuse me?
We'll do it.
No, wait, wait. Are you… Are you kidding?
[Atom Eins] Your husband has qualms.
Can you do it yourself?
[Arthur] No.
Yes.
[Atom Eins] Good.
Then do it.
You're fired.
-[Arthur] Whoa. Hold on.
-[Dame Sylvia] You can't be serious.
Absolutely.
You disobeyed a direct order.
Ah, you need me.
[Atom Eins] No more it seems.
So pack your things.
You can take the rest of the day
to organize your transport.
If you're still on the island at
the end of the day, you'll be trespassing.
And you may be shot.
[chuckles]
-That was amazing.
-Yeah. [chuckles]
The pronunciation is a bit tricky,
but I'll get it.
I'm gonna… I'm gonna
be honest with you, uh…
I think it was a mistake
bringing them here. [stammers]
Species from other worlds,
-millions of years old.
-Hmm.
Do you know how lucky we are
they didn't escape in the crash?
They didn't ask to come here.
Don't do that.
You-You give them thoughts and feelings.
They're killers.
So are we.
Not like that.
We've got brains, you know?
We… We think. We…
Hmm.
We have community.
They survive, eat, sleep, maybe.
-That's it.
-Mmm.
Bees do that.
Ants do that.
They have hives, systems, whole colonies.
It tried to kill us.
Not this one.
Joe, I think this one could be good.
Marcy.
This is a "yes" place. Not a "no" place.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
[Wendy] The boy genius said that "no"
is the first step to nothing.
Being nothing. Achieving nothing.
And here we say, "yes."
If someone tries to take advantage
of you, tries to hurt you,
then… then "no" gives you power.
It gives you power over your body.
Power over your life.
We don't have to talk about this.
Not today.
It has been a crazy few days.
I'm so proud of you. I…
I can't imagine
how hard all this has been.
It's not gonna be forever. I promise.
I'm working out a way
to get us out of here.
What if I don't want to go?
[♪ "Tessellate" plays]
♪ Bite chunks out of me ♪
-♪ You're a shark, and I'm swimming ♪
-[door opens]
♪ My heart still thumps as I bleed ♪
♪ And all your friends come sniffing ♪
♪ Triangles are my favorite shape ♪
♪ Three points where two lines meet ♪
♪ Toe-to-toe, back-to-back, let's go ♪
♪ My love, it's very late ♪
[sighs]
♪ 'Til morning comes ♪
♪ Let's tessellate ♪
-[♪ song ends]
-Good morning. I'm Barrister McAfee.
The moderator assigned to you
by the governing collective
known as The Five.
As agreed upon by your corporations,
the decision I reach
after hearing evidence and arguments
will be legally binding.
Mr. Kavalier, Ms. Yutani,
I expect
you will comport yourselves professionally
as these are professional matters.
Ms. Yutani,
I will now hear your opening statement.
Let me start by listing the facts
that are not in dispute.
First, the USCSS Maginot
is a Science Class research vessel
owned and operated
by the Weyland-Yutani Corporation.
This means
that all data, equipment, personnel,
and research materials on board
are the sole property of Weyland-Yutani.
Seizure and retention of these items is--
-Sorry, can I… can I--
-No.
-Your ship…
-Wait your turn.
…didn't just crash in the abstract.
It destroyed three blocks of my city,
killing and injuring thousands.
[McAfee] Mr. Kavalier,
you will have a chance to speak,
but this is Ms. Yutani's time.
Yeah, look, I don't know how things are
done here in… [snores] …bureaucracy-ville,
but in the future, where I live,
we move fast, and we make trillions.
I'll compare our earnings to yours
any day.
As I mentioned at the onset,
this is a professional hearing,
and you will conduct yourselves
professionally.
[chuckles] Or what?
Or he'll send you to bed
without your supper, little boy.
Mr. Kavalier, do you dispute
the facts listed by Ms. Yutani?
What, that it's her ship? Yeah, sure.
She can have it back
as soon as I figure out how to remove it
from my building without knocking it over.
And the materials onboard?
Well, let me ask you something.
What if it wasn't an accident?
-What?
-[Boy Kavalier] Yeah.
I'm saying maybe it was an attack.
Or maybe the pilot was drunk, or maybe
the ship was so poorly maintained
that the crash
is a matter of criminal negligence,
which would make her the criminal
and me the victim.
Oh, no, here's a better word. The cop.
Because now it's my job to figure out
why so many of my citizens are dead.
Believe me, we are already
well into investigating what--
If you think I'm gonna let you investigate
your own crash, honey, you're crazy.
I already told you, you will be more than
well-compensated for the damage done.
It's not about money! I mean, I've got…
Honey, I've got money. This is a cover-up.
Do you know
what she's so desperate to get back?
Deep-space biological specimen.
Yeah, invasive species, predatory
that Weyland-Yutani
was smuggling onto the planet
in direct violation
of, like, 50 intercorporate laws.
-Untrue.
-Oh. Do you wanna see the pictures?
Wait.
These are proprietary specimens
meant to be studied
at an off-planet research facility.
Which is where they will be transferred to
the moment Mr. Kavalier
stops holding them hostage.
And yet you can understand
Mr. Kavalier's position.
Which is why we are willing to add
an additional $10 billion to
the settlement for his pain and suffering.
[Boy Kavalier] Twenty.
Fifteen.
Twenty-five.
Twenty it is.
[McAfee] Are we agreed then?
-Yeah. Yeah, we are. [chuckles]
-Yes.
Okay, I'll, uh, box them up
and send them back…
you know,
as soon as the quarantine's over.
-No.
-[Boy Kavalier] Yeah.
Six weeks is the established precedent
for off-world quarantine.
Isn't that right?
That is
what the Brubaker Accord established.
Fifty billion,
and we take possession immediately.
It's just not safe, you know?
For the planet. [sighs]
They don't belong to you.
Well, they're living creatures. I mean,
technically they don't belong to anyone.
Okay, I assume we're done here.
It's 20 billion
on top of practical damages,
and we'll return the specimens
at the end of legal quarantine.
And of course, your thoughts and prayers
for all the victims of the Maginot crash
are always welcome.
On behalf of The Five,
let me just say how pleased I am
we could come to an amenable--
-Oh, shut up.
-[Boy Kavalier] Whoo!
[door closes]
Where are we?
I could have one of the Xenomorphs
by the end of the day.
-Could?
-It's a recruited asset.
There's a strong potential for failure.
And you should know that
Prodigy's increased its on-island security
substantially in the last 24 hours.
Most likely
an expectation of a frontal assault.
What do you recommend?
We destabilize the facility,
and exfil in the chaos.
[footsteps retreating]
[elevator chimes]
Look at you.
The almost human. Self-hating machine.
How you must envy me.
Sure. Yesterday's model,
the incredibly relevant robot.
Who wouldn't want to be you?
What's it like working for a company
that's made you obsolete?
I don't know what you're talking about.
They're cute, your kids
with their shiny new bodies.
I gotta get me one of those.
A child or a body that isn't so sad?
You know what I like most
about killing synths?
They don't feel pain.
So nothing clouds their minds
when I start chopping them up.
See,
I would imagine it's the pain
that makes it satisfying.
Especially for Cyborgs.
That moment when you realize
you're not a machine after all,
when the first eyeball pops.
[elevator chimes]
I'll see you soon, old toy.
[sighs]
Just a few adjustments, sweetheart, okay?
Isn't that a gift?
To be able to remove the trauma.
[speaks indistinctly]
[grunting, groaning]
Just… a little bit longer, okay?
Hi.
Hi. [chuckles]
You… You feeling better?
Better?
Better than what? I feel fine.
Normal, I guess.
I feel like I slept
for a thousand years though. [sighs]
-[beeps]
-[sighs]
What's up?
Well, I thought…
You said you were gonna have a baby.
Yeah, right.
When?
Oh, a few days ago.
Uh, Curly told me that you said…
A few days ago we were
in the training room and we had that hike.
No, when Slightly and Smee got back
from the crash.
The what?
The crash? [chuckles]
In the city? And you saw
all the animals in the broken zoo.
Stop funnin'.
The scariest thing I remember
from a few days ago
is ghost stories and flashlights.
No, that was…
What's wrong with you?
Nothing. What's wrong with you?
[Wendy] We went to the city, Nibs.
And the ship was crashed.
We had to go through
and save all these people.
And you… you found the eye.
It really scared you.
Stop it.
Stop what?
I don't have any of that.
What's wrong with me?
Well, it's okay.
It's okay. I'm sure you'll get it back.
You do remember going
with Arthur and Dame Sylvia?
When?
Well, after you said
you were gonna have a baby. They…
[Boy Kavalier] "While she slept,
she had a dream.
She dreamt
that the Neverland had come too near.
And that a strange boy
had broken through from it.
He did not alarm her,
for she thought she had seen him before
in the faces of many women
who have no children.
Perhaps he is to be found
in the faces of some mothers also.
But in her dream, he had rent the film
that obscures the Neverland.
And she saw Wendy and John and Michael…"
[Slightly] I know I can.
I just know I can. I need to find him.
[Boy Kavalier] "…peeping through the gap."
[Slightly] No… I…
I… know. I know. I know.
I know, I know.
I know I can. I just need to…
Just leave me alone!
[Smee] Hey.
-Are-Are you okay?
-[Slightly] I'm fine.
[Smee] We're still friends though, right?
Dude, please, I just need
to take care of this stuff, all right?
Ugh. Man, everybody's so cranky here.
It's not fun anymore.
[Slightly] 'Cause not everything's
supposed to be fun.
We-We're grown-ups now.
Being grown-up sucks.
Yeah. Big time.
Can't-Can't we just… I don't know…
-No, I… I've got all this--
-[Smee] Stuff to do. I know.
-[Slightly] Hey, Smee.
-[Smee] No.
[Slightly] Listen.
[sighs] Look, let me… let me…
let me just take care of this stuff,
and I promise later on we can play
all the games you want. [sighs]
Really?
Yeah.
[Slightly sighs]
What are you doing?
Just giving you a grown-up hug.
[both chuckle]
[TV playing, indistinct]
-Hey.
-Hi.
[Hermit] Have you seen Marcy?
No, I haven't seen her.
[Hermit] Okay.
We could… We could go look for her, maybe?
I'm sure she'll turn up.
[chuckles]
Remind me…
what was your name before?
[Morrow] Aarush.
You have to hurry.
I can't.
Oh. If that's not something
you can talk about, I understand.
[Morrow] Say it,
"You need to come with me."
It's just unfair, you know?
You know, like, Wendy
gets to see her family, but what do I get?
We will talk to them, I promise.
Hey, can I, uh…
I want to show you something.
-Uh… What?
-[Slightly] It-It's secret.
I…
Come on, it'll be fun.
-[knocks on door]
-[Rashidi] Hey.
Uh, patrol is short a man. Wanna come?
No. [chuckles] That's rude.
We were just gonna…
It-It won't take long.
We'll talk when I'm back, okay?
[Slightly] No, no, we need to go now.
It's, uh… It's-It's for Wendy.
Sorry, kid, it's my fault.
Orders from above. Security issue.
We'll, uh… We'll bring him back
as soon as possible, all right?
What the hell was that about?
I have no idea.
All right, Q's this way.
Let's get you geared up.
[Siberian] I'd rather be out here
with the bugs, lizards and slugs.
Suits me fine. Scary shit's in that lab.
What, you mean the monsters?
Or one of those freaky-ass robots
having a malfunction, all…
[mimicking mechanical noises]
Sorry, man. Sorry.
Is that really your sister?
In that machine?
Yeah.
I think so.
She is to me, anyway.
I heard Yutani's pissed.
Might send some of her Cyborgs
to get her monsters back.
That's why we're here patrolling.
Got to be on alert.
We're on an island
in the middle of fucking nowhere.
No way on, no way off.
This is just to keep us busy.
There's gotta be some way off, right?
[Rashidi] Some airships, couple boats.
Are we close enough
to the mainland for boats?
I don't know about that,
but keep down this path
and you'll see a sign for boat docks.
It's not like you can just get
a weekend pass though. [chuckles]
Everything is under strict control.
By our people? People we know?
[Rashidi] Nah. Island has
its own security. We're just…
We're the muscle, the help, whatever.
We're expendable.
You know, my dad took me on a boat once.
It was a long time ago.
You guys, you grow up around boats?
Stop.
[Hermit] Stop what?
Whatever you're planning.
Asking about boats, how far we are.
We got a good thing going here.
We're alive. We get paid.
Don't fuck it up.
The monsters are here.
[Siberian] Maybe.
But if I'm here, at least I know.
Know what?
Where they are.
-[Wendy screeching]
-[creature humming, rattling]
[rattling]
[chitters]
[rattling continues]
[clicks]
[Tootles] Hello?
Are you in the lab?
Uh. No. Uh, you left, so…
[Kirsh] I had to fly to the mainland
for a few hours.
There was a meeting with Yutani.
I should be back by dark.
Okay. Uh, what do you need me to do?
[Kirsh] The creatures need to be fed
and watered.
Check the data from last night, and
pick the next experiment from the list.
Is Curly with you?
-Uh…
-[Curly] That was a big splash.
No. But I can handle it.
Step-by-step.
Follow protocols to the letter.
The scientific method is a method,
not a suggestion box.
I got it.
Um…
I have to go.
-Kirsh needs me for something in the lab.
-Should I come?
No. I got it.
Bye.
-Have you really… Oh!
-Oh!
[door opens]
[beeps]
[sheep bleats]
[distorted bleating]
[sighing]
[door rattles]
[creature rustling]
[creature skittering]
[breathing heavily]
Good boy.
[grunting]
[choking]
[mechanical whirring]
[whirring stops]
[Boy Kavalier] "The boys
on the island vary, of course, in numbers,
according as they get killed and so on.
When they seem to be growing up,
which is against the rules…
Peter thins them out."
Wendy?
[Wendy] What did you do to her?
Who?
[Wendy] Nibs.
She doesn't remember
half the stuff we did this week.
Not the crash, not the fighting,
that she said she was gonna have a baby.
Well, darling, it's, uh…
complicated.
You know she was upset.
We ran some diagnostics, and we found
a glitch in one of her subroutines.
-The only way we could fix it--
-You made her forget.
We removed the corrupt data
before it could corrupt the rest of her.
[Wendy] That's a funny word.
Corrupt.
-[Dame Sylvia] It means--
-I know what it means. I'm not stupid.
No. Of course not.
I told him this was a "yes" place.
You didn't give her a choice, did you?
I gave her medicine,
just like any other doctor.
Please, Wendy, I have
the utmost respect for you. All of you.
Because we're special.
Of course.
You are.
You have potential
beyond anything we imagined.
You've been going to the secure lab
a lot lately, Kirsh told me.
Someone has to watch.
They didn't ask to come here.
Well…
They're specimens.
Collected by Weyland-Yutani.
He's studying them.
They're experiments to him.
This is a research facility
filled with scientists.
That's what we do. We study.
Like you study us.
Wendy.
That's not my name.
Marcy. Marcy, why don't we sit down--
He said, "Stop pretending."
I said,
"Are we people or are we something else?"
And he said, "Stop pretending
to be people." And I think he's right.
I don't want to be people anymore
if this is what people are.
Killing things, taking them apart
just to see what's inside.
-Who said?
-[Wendy] Kirsh.
He said people get romantic about things.
Feelings.
But that we don't have to.
We can get rid of all of that.
All the sadness.
All the madness.
See the world for what it really is,
not how it feels.
Well, he would say that.
He's a machine.
Marcy. Trust me.
Everything we're doing here,
we do for you.
My only job is to make sure
that nothing gets lost.
Nibs got lost.
No. We helped her.
Are there going to be problems
in this transition?
Of course. It's new technology.
You're on a journey that no one's
ever taken before.
But we're here.
I'm here to help you.
To make sure that you get through.
But we have to work together, right?
You have to tell me what's wrong,
so I can help you fix it.
What if you're what's wrong?
[door opens]
-[sighs]
-[door closes]
[person] You got a second?
[Arthur] Oh, hi.
Hi.
Joe, right? Or do you prefer Hermit?
What are you doing?
Oh, me? Nothing.
Just getting out of here. Quick trip.
Not like I was fired or anything.
They fired you?
No.
Oh. [stutters] Yes. But don't worry
about me. I have, like, six degrees.
Sorry, did-did you want something?
Yeah. I, uh…
I noticed how you took care of Marcy…
Wendy.
When her hearing…
Anyway, I noticed how you seem to care.
Yeah, I did. I mean, I… I do.
So, maybe I can ask you something
and you can give me an honest answer,
and then maybe
I can just relax a little bit.
Yeah. Well, most of what we do here
is pretty confidential,
but I'll answer what I can.
Is my sister safe here?
Oh.
Be honest. Please.
[Arthur] Of course she is.
As safe as a safe in a bank.
And the missus and me do everything
we can to ensure the kids' well-being.
Here, let me show you.
I can pop their vitals right here.
Come on.
See, there's Smee. Looking healthy.
And then there's Wendy.
[Hermit] Yeah.
-I see.
-Yeah?
And look. Uh… [punches keys]
H-Here's, um, Wendy's vitals.
Looking totally normal.
That's all the reassurances
I can give you.
We do everything we can for them.
Best care. All the time.
Yeah. That's really all I needed to hear.
Thank you.
Have a good trip.
[computer beeps]
What?
[punching keys]
[computer beeps]
Shit.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
[breathing shakily]
I can't do it. [sighs]
I can't get a person in.
[Morrow] Sure, you can. You're a good boy.
Do you want to say goodbye
to your mother before she dies?
No, no, no, no, no, no. Please.
Please, I'll… I'll try. I'll try.
Just-Just give me one more chance, please.
Please don't do anything to her. Please?
[breathing shakily] Huh?
Come in. Can you hear me?
Hello? [breathing shakily]
[Arthur] Are you looking for Tootles?
His tracker is offline. You seen him?
No.
No, uh, Kirsh asked me
to watch his stuff, so…
-He didn't give me--
-Yeah.
Tootles?
[breathing shakily]
[Arthur punching keys]
[beeps]
[Arthur] Oh, no.
No, no, no, no. No.
[cries] Tootles.
-[beeps]
-[Arthur] Tootles.
[panting]
[chitters]
Slightly.
Slightly!
I need your help.
[grunts, panting]
[creature skittering]
[clattering]
[beeping]
[panting]
Can you open it from the outside?
I'm locked in.
Slightly, open the door from the outside.
He has my family.
What?
I have a family too.
-I have a family.
-[metal clangs]
[creatures screeching]
[creature screeches]
[metal clattering]
Hey, Ops, this is Dr. Sylvia in--
[creature screeches]
[Arthur screaming]
[Arthur choking]
[Arthur groaning]
-[breathing shakily, sniffles]
-[Arthur screaming]
[thuds]
[Boy Kavalier] Whoo-hoo!
Whoo!
[chuckles] Yeah.
[chuckles] Wow.
[chuckles]
Everything okay?
Affirmative.
[door beeps]
[creatures rumbling, screeching]
Arthur.
[breathing shakily]
[grunts]
[creature buzzing]
[creature rumbling]
[sheep bleating]
[♪ "Keep Away" playing]
♪ Sickness spilling through your eyes ♪
♪ Cravin' everything
That you thought was alive ♪
♪ Stab me in my heart again ♪
♪ Ah, yeah ♪
♪ Drag me through your wasted life
Are you forever dead? ♪
♪ Do like I told you
Stay away from me ♪
♪ Never misunderstand me
Keep away from me ♪
♪ Yeah ♪
♪ Ah, yeah
Keep away from me ♪
♪ Oh, yeah ♪
♪ Never misunderstand me ♪
♪ Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
[♪ song ends]
[♪ dramatic music plays]
[♪ music ends]